#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

David has been involved in major IT projects including the development and integration of various business and customer facing applications into telecommunication, internet and travel systems over a 18 year period.

His early career saw him in the role of software and systems engineer where he acquired skills developing software within structured software development methodologies. Later on David was able to apply his software engineering skills in the design of application based architecture. As his knowledge of software and business systems improved David was able to function at team management level, in the role of Solutions Architect providing solution designs based on business requirements. His knowledge and experience has often put him in the role of Technical Consultant to the business domain, helping the business leverage existing technology and embracing new ones.

## **EXPERTISE**

- Over 12 years experience in Solutions Architecture and Development
- Over 9 years experience in the design of Business Solutions
- Over 7 years experience providing integration solutions with various ESBs
- Over 6 years experience developing system integration solutions in C, Perl, java.and SQL
- Over 4 years experience in front end development
- Over 3 years of web services, microservices and REST API design
- Proficient in programming languages such as Perl, C/C++, Java and unix shell programming..
- Significant experience in scripting languages such as python and Javascript
- Proficient in multiple operating systems, including Windows, Solaris, Linux and FreeBSD.
- Proficient in 4th generation languages such as HTML, XML, SQL.
- Thorough knowledge of the full TCP/IP protocol suite as well as HTTP and SMTP.
- Qualified and experienced in agile based software delivery.
- Proficient in the use of various source control applications and IDEs.
- TOGAF 9.1 certified

# **David George**

## Solution Architect

#### **Education & Certificates**

## 1997-1998 Salford University Salford, UK

Ms., Information Technology Management.

## 1989- 1992 University of the West Indies Trinidad

- Bsc. Surveying .
- Graduated with upper second degree honours.

## Courses & Trainings

#### 2017 Swisscom

Certified Scale Agile Practitioner

## 2004 Exim, Cambridge University

• Exim Mail systems

#### 2004 Portal/Oracle Billing Systems

- Infranet Essentials (6.5)
- Infranet Architecture and API (6.5)
- Infranet Developer (6.5)

#### 2002 Mirapoint

- Mirapoint Systems
- Mirapoint Certified Engineer (Email Platform)

#### 2002 Zeus

• Zeus Virtual ISP Platform

## 2002

#### Sun Systems

• Solaris System Administrator II

Page 2 of 6

Solution Architect

#### **PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE**

Dec 2018 - Present

#### Caravan and Motorhome Members Club, UK

Solutions Architect

- Provide Governance of Architectural principles on Booking Capability eCommerce project
- Provide Technical Expertise for implementing online Booking System
- Produce HLDs
- Review LLDs from suppliers
- Prepare Non-Functional requirements based on business requirements
- Implement digital solutions for online membership experience, also Analytics for usage and ecommerce tracking on an SPA.
- Integration of web booking application with CMS backend
- Design solutions on technology stack which includes Microsoft .NET and RabbitMQ.
- Present Technical solutions for approval from a Technical Architecture Board
- SAP ERP integration
- Design solutions involving .Net APIs on CA Gateway
- Implementation of WorldPay based card payment system with external suppliers
- Implementation of DTMF PCI compliant card payment system with external suppliers

#### Integrella Ltd, London

Senior API Consultant/Architect

- Design RESTful based API solutions.
- Provide API management support to major clients across EMEA region, including Kingfisher and Barclays.
- Designed TOGAF based Business Process model artefact for Great Ormond Street Hospital.
- Designed Application layer and Technology layer models for Chelsea and Westminster NHS Trust.
- Designed PSD2 based API proposal based on Open banking standards with Authentication Broker and Message Origin Authentication SOA Design Patterns.

Nov 2017 - Mar 2018

Jan 2013 - Oct 2017

#### Solution Architect

#### Swisscom AG Bern, Switzerland

Technical Billing Consultant/Domain Architect

- Worked within Agile/DevOps environment
- Integration of CRM with Billing and invoicing applications..
- Integration of testing solution within SOA ESB Design Pattern
- Analyse Business requirements and review functional specifications for SAP RM-CA changes.
- POC of service deployment on AWS
- Integration of Billing and Revenue management with testing solutions.
- Analyse Business requirements and review functional specifications for Oracle Billing system.

## Apr 2011 - Dec 2012

## Travelport Ltd, Langley, UK

**Technical Billing Consultant** 

- Design and Implement E2E Order management, Billing and invoicing solution
- Integration of Legacy data/systems with new Oracle Billing System using Webservices.
- Use of Agnostic SOA Design Pattern
- Use of TOGAF elements to achieve target architecture.
- Design Billing Solution using Oracle BRM and Web-services.
- Worked with stakeholders to produce full system analysis.
- Design Business Intelligence solution with Oracle BI

#### Feb 2009 - Mar 2011

#### Swisscom AG Bern, Switzerland

Lead Architect

- Provide Solution for Billing Migration Project.
- Migration to Oracle BRM using Web-services.
- Integration of Order Management with Billing solution
- Integration of Billing System with Revenue Management system
- Use of ESB SOA Design Pattern with TIBCO ESB
- Use of Java, Oracle DB.
- Use of TOGAF elements to achieve target architecture.

Email: david.l.george@gmail.com tel: +447973817587 Page

#### Solution Architect

May 2007 - Jan 2009

## Thus (A Cable and Wireless Business) London, UK

Snr Software and Systems Engineer

- Provide technical management to the Billing and Revenue Management development team
- Use of Authentication Broker and messaging SOA Design Pattern.
- Responsible for Design and development of customizations for the enterprise Order management and Billing systems utilizing C/C++, Perl and Java with PL/SQL in Oracle database on Solaris OS.
- Design invoicing layouts using JavaScript and CSS.
- Designed and implemented KPIs and SLAs for software and systems development.

Jun 2005 - Apr 2007

#### Orange UK, St. Albans

**Billing Application Specialist** 

- Troubleshoot and resolved operational issues for Billing, and Provisioning systems
- Provide solutions for BRM business reports from Oracle database using Perl, shell script and PL/SQL.
- Acted as Consultant and Solutions Architect on major projects including the implementation of pre-rated Video on demand (IP TV) services within Oracle BRM using UML.
- Designed and implemented monitoring solutions for Oracle BRM on Solaris OS utilizing Oracle DB, shell and perl scripting

Solution Architect

Jul 1999 – May 2005

#### Thus Group Plc Gateway House, London

Software and Systems Engineer

- ASP, C# .NET design and development to provide Microsoft provisioning platform. Created application interfaces from order management to the BRM Billing system using perl CGI, javascript and CSS.
- Utilised Solaris and Oracle technologies to develop provisioniing and billing solutions
- Developed Direct Debit Billing capability for Broadband and Standard Dial Up products for online order systems.
- Developed Direct Debit Data Module within BRM for validating and processing Direct Debit payments in C/C++.
- Integrated web application with BRM billing system using tcp/ip suite of technologies, Soap with WSDL, Java and Corba.
- Utilised database technologies such as Oracle PLSQL, MS SQL and My SQL to apply business rules to applications and also to generate dynamic content.
- Integrated middle tier business systems with broadband provisioning systems through the development of provisioning APIs.
- Supported Internet technology infrastructure including radius authentication servers, email hubs, routers and switches.
- Designed and implement integration solutions for the billing and provisioning systems.
- Designed, implemented and supported Business Systems across the Enterprise.
- Designed, developed, implemented and maintained extensive Corba based services in OO Perl modules used as middleware infrastructure.
- Designed and developed application modules to implement business rules and policies as part of online registration systems.

Email: david.l.george@gmail.com tel: +447973817587 Page